

SKILLS

Website Development

React Next JS Node JS Javascript **Typescript** Redux Prisma MongoDB PostgreSQL MySQL HTML CSS

Others

React Native Docker Java C++



CONTACT

- ☆ Islamabad, Pakistan
- **** +923029531121
- ✓ workwithusamabilal@gmail.com
- usamabilal.com
- in www.linkedin.com/in/usamabilal 775/
- CodeWUsama

USAMA BILAL

WEB DEVELOPER (MERN)

INTRODUCTION & EXPERTISE

A passionate software engineer having 2 years of industrial experience. My expertise are in web development particularly in frontend using React & Next JS. I also have working experience in Node JS, MongoDB & PostgreSQL. I am an analytical thinker and enjoy breaking down complex problems into manageable components and leading the team front the front to success.

EXPERIENCE

June 2022 Present

Devsinc, Islamabad

Software Engineer

Leading the frontend team of US based referral

platfrom using React & Next is

OCTOBER

Pakistan Air Force Headquarters, Islamabad

2021 - May 2022 Software Engineer (MERN)

Worked as a software engineer on two major software solutions for defense using MERN

stack.

June 2021 -September 2021 Junior Frontend Engineer

Embrace IT, Islamabad

Worked on the frontend of HRMS application

using React JS

HIGHLIGHTED PROJECTS

2022 - Present

BOON - REFERRAL HIRING PLATFORM

US based project through Devsinc

Leading the frontend team for automated and

engaging employee referral platform.

2021

WORKSPACE

Embrace IT inhouse product

Company management platform to post jobs, manage candidates, conduct interviews and project meetings & manage employees finances.

2021

DIGITAL WALLET

Freelance

Digital wallet managment app build in React

Native, Node JS & MongoDB.

2020-2021

WEBSITE CREATOR USING PRESETS

FYP for Comsats University Islamabad

Final Year Project- A platform build in MERN stack for a laymen to modify the provided templates and

publish websites.

EDUCATION

2017 - 2021

BS Computer Science

COMSATS University, Islamabad CGPA: 3.74 (Gold Medalist)

2015 - 2017

F.Sc. Pre-Engineering

Army College, Sargodha Marks: 85%

ACHIEVEMENTS

Employee of the quarter

Awarded with several quarterly awards in Devsinc.

Batch Position Holder - Gold Medalist

First position in the computer science department for batch 2017-2021 in COMSATS

INTERESTS AND HOBBIES

Logic Building

Logic building for custom algorithms

Problem Solving

I enjoy analyzing complex issues, identifying key factors, and developing a clear plan of action to tackle the problem.

INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

- Project Management
- Leadership
- Team Player
- Time Management